the goal of parenting by way of
养育途经目标
introduction my purpose is to present
介绍我的目的是介绍
truths from God's Word that define this
来自上帝之道的真理定义了这一点
goal of parenting by understanding the
通过理解养育孩子的目标
scriptures that we will consider today
今天 我们会考虑经文
and their implications you will be
和他们的影响，你会
better equipped to live out these
更好地装备这些
scriptures in your own ministry to your
在你自己的事工中的经文
children and also to counsel parents and
孩子们也为父母和孩子提供咨询
families more accurately from God's Word
家庭更准确地来自上帝的话语
the big picture of Christian parenting
基督教育儿的大局
has three pillars the first one is the
有三个支柱，第一个是支柱
motive or the goal the second is effort
动机或目标第二是努力
in evangelism and the third is effort in
在传福音中，第三是努力
teaching and training when this
这时教学和训练
structure is in place then we're doing
结构到位， 然后我们正在做
our best as parents to bring glory and
我们最好的父母带来荣耀和
honor to God
荣耀归于上帝
so using this building as a metaphor for
所以用这个建筑作为隐喻
the Christian home that honors God we
我们尊敬上帝的基督徒家园
have these three essential pillars in
拥有这三个必不可少的支柱
the area where you're sitting there are
你坐在那里的地方
the three large pillars the the glulam
胶合木的三大支柱
beams of the 40s and 50s that are really
真的是40年代和50年代的光束
keeping the roof from falling down on
防止屋顶倒塌
you right now and so they've been there
你现在，所以他们一直在那里
for a long time and they're doing their
很长一段时间，他们正在做他们的
job well I believe that these three
工作顺利我相信这三个
principles that we're going to consider
我们将要考虑的原则
in the introduction are for a Christian
在介绍中是为了一个基督徒
family kind of what those pillars are
这些支柱是什么样的家庭
for you they're the framework that keeps
对你来说， 他们是保持的框架
everything in place and enables
一切就绪并启用
everything that God intends to go on
上帝打算继续下去的一切
inside that family to go smoothly to be
在那个家庭里面顺利进行
done with the the most effective nature
完成最有效的性质
in glorifying God so let's let's
在荣耀上帝的时候让我们放手吧
consider these three pillars the first
考虑这三个支柱第一
pillar of a family that's seeking to
多数民众赞成寻求一个家庭的顶梁柱
glorify God is the goal or the motive
荣耀上帝是目标或动机
the Galatians 1:10 Paul writes for
加拉太书1:10保罗说的
am I now seeking the favor of men or of
我现在正在寻求男人或女人的青睐
God or am I still striving to please men
上帝或我仍在努力取悦男人
if I were still trying to please men I
如果我还在努力取悦男人我
would not be a bondservant of Christ
不会成为基督的仆人
so rather than please ourselves or our
而不是取悦自己或我们的
kids or other people the motive the
孩子或其他人的动机
purpose in the Christian home is to
在基督徒家中的目的是
bring glory to God to please him well
为上帝带来荣耀，以取悦他
what does it look like in families in
它 在家庭中的样子是什么样的
our culture where there's a different
我们的文化与众不同
motive than pleasing God what are the
动机不是取悦上帝是什么
purposes of some parents well some
一些父母的目的很好
parents seek to honor themselves rather
父母寻求兑现 自己，而
than God and so they use their
比上帝，所以他们使用他们的
children's outward obedience or
孩子的外在顺从或
intelligence to show their peers what
情报向同行展示了什么
good parents they are others seek to
他们是其他人寻求的好父母
honor their children above all rather
荣誉高于一切，而他们的孩子
than honoring God so they are obsessed
而不是尊重上帝，所以他们被痴迷
with helping their children excel in
帮助他们的孩子擅长
school or sports or their social status
学校或体育或他们的社会地位
some parents seek to prove to their own
有些父母试图向自己证明
parents that they're actually good
父母，他们真的很好
parents and so they focus on how well
父母，所以他们专注于如何
their children achieve or behave for us
他们的孩子为我们实现或表现
as parents we need to consider what is
作为父母， 我们需要考虑是什么
our primary motive what is our purpose
我们的主要动机是什么？
the parent seeking God's honor is living
寻求上帝荣誉的父母是活着的
by Galatians 1:10 the second pillar that
加拉太书1:10 第二支柱
we must set in place in our homes is
我们必须在我们的家中设置到位
effort in evangelism why do I say effort
传福音的努力为什么我要说努力
in evangelism rather than the salvation
在传福音而不是救恩
of your child the truth is that there's
你孩子的真相是有的
nothing we can do as people that can
什么可以作为人们这样做 可以
cause the salvation of someone else
引起别人的救赎
including our own children consider how
包括我们自己的孩子考虑如何
the book of Ephesians describes the
以弗所书描述了
events
事件
that resulted in your own salvation if
这导致了你自己的救赎
you are indeed a believer today in
你今天确实是一个信徒
chapter 2 verses 4 & 5 we read but God
第2章经文4和5我们读了但是上帝
even when we were dead in our
即使我们死在我们的身上
transgressions made us alive together
犯罪使我们共同生活
with Christ by grace you have been saved
借着恩典得到了基督， 你们得救了
so the action of God's saving us was
所以上帝拯救我们的行为是
according to the choice he made before
根据他之前的选择
he created the world according to
他根据创造的世界
Ephesians 1 for no human being had the
以弗所书1对没有人有
ability to cause you or me to be saved
使你或我得救的能力
salvation is God's work so he is the one
救恩是上帝的工作，所以他就是那个人
who gave each believer the gift of faith
谁给了每个信徒信仰的礼物
in the gospel according to Ephesians 2:8
根据以弗所书2：8 ，在福音书中
and 9 he is also the one who has the
9他也是拥有的人
ability to cause each of our children to
能够引起我们每个孩子的注意力
be saved if they will be saved
如果他们将被保存，他们将被保存
so our part as parents is not the
所以我们作为父母的部分不是
salvation of our children but it's the
拯救我们的孩子，但它是
effort and evangelism how can we become
努力和传福音我们怎样才能成为
great at this effort and evangelism I
伟大的这种努力和我传福音
suggest three things they're listed in
提出他们列出的三件事
your conference notebook first pray
你的会议笔记本首先祈祷
first Timothy 2 verses 1 through 8
提摩太前书2节经文1到8节
instructs us to pray for all sorts of
指示我们为各种各样的祈祷
unbelievers commit yourself to
不信的人承诺
faithfully pray for your unbelieving
忠实地为你不信的祷告
children second communicate the gospel
孩子们第二次传播福音
this sounds simple but you will find
这听起来很简单，但你会发现
many parents who come to you for help
很多父母来找你帮忙
who have unbelieving children who have
谁有不信的孩子谁有
not done this Paul tells us in 1st
没有这样，保罗在第一节告诉我们
Corinthians 3 that we are to plant the
哥林多前书3我们要种植
seed of the gospel and water it only God
福音的种子和水只有上帝
has the ability to cause that seed to
有能力使种子成为
germinate and to grow but we must do our
发芽和成长，但我们必须做我们的
part by communicating the gospel clearly
部分通过清楚地传达福音
and accurately according to the age of
并准确地根据年龄
the child and their level of biblical
孩子和他们的圣经水平
understanding
理解
the third part is demonstrate the gospel
第三部分是展示福音
in first Timothy the Apostle Paul exhort
在第一提摩太使徒保罗劝诫
stimm ëthey the Ephesian pastor to show
以弗所牧师要表现出来
himself as an example of those who
他自己就是那些人的榜样
believe first Timothy 4:12 doing so
首先相信蒂莫西4:12这样做
requires the church leader to discipline
要求教会领袖训练
himself for the purpose of godliness to
亲自为敬虔的目的
be absorbed in actions of righteousness
专注于正义的行为
and to take pains with these things so
并且用这些东西来解决问题
there's a lot involved in demonstrating
有很多参与演示
the gospel according to this passage
根据该通道 的福音
just as that church leader would be more
正如教会领袖会更多
effective in ministry by living such a
通过生活这样一个有效的事工
life so also you as the parent or leader
生活也是你作为父母或领导者的生活
in your household or your council II as
在你的家庭或你的理事会II中
the parent and leader in their household
他们家中的父母和领导者
will honor God and enhance their
将尊重上帝，并提升他们的
ministry to their children if the parent
如果父母，他们的孩子的事工
is living a life that shows increasing
生活越来越多
victory over sin and thus exemplifies a
战胜罪恶，从而例证了一个
person who isn't weld by the Almighty
不是全能者焊接的人
God this demonstrates the gospel one of
上帝这表明了福音之一
the most important things I believe it
我相信最重要的事情
for parents is being real with kids kids
对于父母来说，孩子们的孩子是真实的
may not seem interested in noticing that
可能似乎没有兴趣注意到这一点
the parents are making progress and
父母正在取得进步
sanctification that they used to sin in
他们过去犯罪的成圣
that way and now they don't and they're
这样，现在他们没有，他们是
saying this is because of God's grace
说这是因为上帝的恩典
and his word but if we let them in on
和他的话，但如果我们让他们继续
our efforts to become more like Christ
我们努力变得更像基督
and they observe that actually
他们实际观察到了
transpiring then as the years go by and
随着岁月的流逝而逐渐发生
as they get older you may be the only
随着年龄的增长，你可能是唯一的
person they know who whose belief system
他们知道谁的信仰体系
actually results in change and being
实际上会导致变化和存在
able to solve problems if so that will
能够解决问题，如果是这样的话
open the door to communication the third
打开第三通信的大门
pillar
支柱
that we as parents must set in place in
我们作为父母必须设置到位
our homes is effort in teaching and
我们的家是努力的教学和
training proverbs 4 verses 1 and 2 hero
训练谚语4节1和2英雄
sons the instruction of a father and
父亲和父亲的指示
give attention that you may gain
注意你可能会获得
understanding for I give you sound
了解我给你的声音
teaching do not abandon my instruction
教学不要放弃我的指导
if your child is born again and has a
如果你的孩子重生并且有一个孩子
new life in Christ teaching and training
基督教会和训练中的新生活
are essential in your ministry if your
如果你的，你的事工是必不可少的
child is not a believer then he cannot
孩子不是信徒然后他不能
consistently obey God he can't overcome
一贯服从上帝，他无法克服
sin according to Romans 8 verses 6
根据罗8节6罪
through 8 what about that child how do
通过8 那个孩子怎么做
you teach and train them well by
你教好和训练他们
teaching him God's standard as he fails
当他失败时，教导他上帝的标准
to reach it God will use his word to
要达到它，上帝会用他的话来
convict your child of sin this will show
这将证明你的孩子犯了罪
him that he is not self-sufficient and
他，他不是自给自足的
that he is not always able to obey even
他并不总是能够服从
when he really wants to this realization
当他真的想要 实现这个目标的时候
shows him his need for the gospel here's
向他展示了他对福音的需要
a photo of the spring flowers in the
一张春天的花朵照片
Antelope Valley where I live when I was
羚羊谷我住的地方时，我是
walking in this field I took a deep
走在这个领域，我深深地走了
breath and the flower smelled so good
呼吸，花闻起来很好
but not everybody walking in a field
但不是每个人都走在田野里
like that
像那样
in April breathing in deeply would have
在四月深呼吸会有
the same view would they some of you are
他们中的一些人会有同样的看法
nodding your head right now that you're
现在点点头，你就是这样
in that group for the person with
在那个组中为谁
allergies that's a pretty picture but
过敏，这是一个漂亮的图片，但
you wouldn't want to be there would you
你不想在那里
well 2nd Corinthians 2 15 and 16
第二次哥林多前书2 15和16
describes a similar contrast and this is
描述了一个类似的对比，这是
a contrast that goes on in the home of
在家里发生的对比
and parents where there may be children
还有可能有孩子的父母
who are believers and there are others
谁是信徒，还有其他人
who are not your life as a strong
谁不是你强大的生活
Christian who loves God is quote a
热爱上帝的基督徒引用了一句话
fragrance of Christ to God among those
这些基督在上帝面前的香气
who are being saved and among those who
谁 被保存，并在那些谁
are perishing to the one an aroma of
正在消灭一种香气
death to death to the other an aroma of
死到死对方的香气
life to life your example in your
生活就是你生命中的榜样
teaching of God's Word will be received
将接受上帝圣言的教导
generally by children who are believers
通常是信徒的孩子
as useful help in their walk with Christ
作为与基督同行的有用帮助
but to the unbeliever who does not want
但对于不想要的不信的人
to obey God to them that same truth
向他们服从上帝同样的真理
doesn't smell so sweet what should we
闻起来不那么甜我们该怎么办？
conclude about this accomplish your
总结一下这个完成你的
motive of honoring God accomplish that
尊重上帝的动机实现了这一点
goal by teaching his word to strengthen
通过教导他的话加强目标
the believer and to point the unbeliever
信徒和点不信
to their need for Jesus Christ each day
他们需要对耶稣基督的每一天
when you accomplish this goal of
当你实现这个目标时
honoring God you'll be content you're
尊重上帝， 你会满足于你
honoring him you're accomplishing what
尊重他，你正在完成什么
he's given you to do as the parent of
他赐给你做父母的
the believer and of the unbeliever what
信徒和不信的人是什么
if you are not sure if your child is a
如果你不确定你的孩子是不是
Christian or not many parents are not
基督徒或没有多少父母不是
sure so what evidence might answer this
确定有什么证据可以回答这个问题
question well scripture tells us that
问题以及圣经告诉我们，
bearing fruit proves the authenticity of
结果证明了它的真实性
a professing believers faith john 15 9
一位自称信徒的信徒约翰15 9
but how much fruit is necessary and how
但需要多少水果和如何
do you measure fruit such as replacing
你测量水果，如更换
sin with righteousness in a 6 year old
在一个6岁的孩子身上犯了正义罪
or a 10 year old or what about the teen
或者10 岁或者是青少年
who's made a profession of faith but
谁是信仰专业但是
they seem to be lacking consistent fruit
他们似乎缺乏一致的果实
right now many parents of such kids do
现在很多这样的孩子的父母都这样做
not believe they have enough evidence to
不相信他们有足够的 证据
know for sure if they are truly saved
知道他们是否真的得救了
God knows when we do not and one day we
天知道什么时候我们不知道，有一天我们
will all know but between now and then
从现在到现在都会知道
for the believer and the unbeliever
为信徒和不信的人
accomplish your goal is apparent teach
实现你的目标是明显的教导
the Word of God in your home another
另一个在你家里的神的话语
point about our effort in teaching and
关于我们在教学方面的努力
training children is this you as parents
培养孩子这就是你作为父母
must accept the responsibility to lead
必须承担领导的责任
and teach and train your children one of
并教导和训练你的孩子之一
the most common issues that you'll find
你会发现最常见的问题
in people who come to you for counsel
在那些来找你咨询的人
from the word and the presenting problem
从单词和呈现问题
is my house is a mess is this right here
我的房子是乱七八糟的就在这里
parents who are not teaching or leading
没有教学或领导的父母
or training their children these days
或者这些天训练他们的孩子
too many parents believe it does take a
太多的父母认为这确实需要一个
village to raise their children so many
村里抚养孩子这么多
Christian parents accept their place
基督徒父母接受他们的位置
alongside YouTube videos animated movies
与YouTube视频动画电影一起
friends the teacher Justin Bieber
朋友老师贾斯汀·比伯
internet sites parents accept their
网站父母接受他们的
place among all these others as Cola
把所有这些人当作可乐
thora teas for their children and their
为他们的孩子和他们的孩子们提供的茶
children are learning what they perceive
孩子们正在学习他们所感知的东西
to be truth from each of these and no
从这些中得到真相，不是
one has ever told them that any of these
有人告诉过他们这些
carry more weight than the other but God
比上帝更重要
says that obeying you the parent will
说父母愿意服从你
result in long life in Ephesians 6 1 & 2
导致以弗所书6 1和2的长寿
the source of instruction for the child
孩子的教学来源
is the parent the commandment with the
是诫命的父母
promise that they'll live long is to
保证他们会长寿
obey mom and
服从妈妈和
according to the word these other
根据这些字
influences in the child's life have
在孩子的生活影响有
neither the responsibility nor the same
既不是责任也不是相同
place of authority that's held by the
由...持有的权力的地方
parents
父母
well if you and your children live by
好吧，如果你和你的孩子住在一起
this truth from God's Word you will be
你将会从神的话语中得到这个真理
regarded by most people as freaks
被大多数人视为怪胎
obeying parents hasn't really been
服从父母的确没有
popular in our culture since 1959 can I
我自1959年以来在我们的文化中流行
tell you that Christians following God's
告诉你基督徒跟随上帝的
standards have perhaps never really fit
标准可能从未真正适合
in to the society norm think about the
在社会规范中思考
1930s American family that family was
20世纪30年代的美国家庭认为家庭是
about dad working so that they could
关于爸爸的工作，他们可以
survive during the Depression so the
在大萧条时期生存下来，因此
American work ethic overshadowed
美国的职业道德黯然失色
dependence on God that was the
依赖上帝就是这样
foundation of the Christian home and
基督徒家庭和基督徒的基础
then there were the 50s the biblical
然后有50年代的圣经
balance of love and discipline probably
可能是爱与纪律的平衡
seemed really odd to many parents and
对很多父母而言，这似乎很奇怪
kids in the disciplined focused family
在纪律严明的家庭中的孩子们
of the 1950s one of my favorite things
20世纪50年代我喜欢的东西之一
is talking to Christians from different
与不同的基督徒交谈
eras older Christians and it is
比较年长的基督徒，它是
interesting because sometimes it seems
有趣， 因为有时它似乎
like gee our society is just going so
就像我们的社会一样
far away from God's Word and where we
远离神的话语和我们所处的位置
are so different if we walk by God's
如果我们走向上帝的话，是如此不同
Word in our culture but really we talk
在我们的文化中说话但我们真的在说话
to him most people who were striving to
对他来说，大多数人都在努力
live by the word in the 50s or the 30s
生活在50年代或30年代
and I'll tell you they they didn't
我会告诉你他们没有
really fit in either well then in the
真的适合在那么好
70s love was redefined as tolerance and
70年代的爱被重新定义为宽容和
that didn't really fit in with honoring
这并不符合尊重
God above all either
上帝也是最重要的
that didn't fit with the balance of
这不符合平衡
biblical love and discipline that does
圣经的爱和纪律，做
exist in the home that is honoring God
存在于尊重上帝的家中
so as our predecessors let us be glad to
所以我们的前辈让我们感到高兴
follow God's Word in parenting according
按照上帝的教养方式遵循上帝的话语
to the scriptures even if that means
即使这意味着经文
that we will not fit in with the culture
我们不适应文化
of our day so teach your children God's
我们这一天所以教你的孩子上帝的
Word to do so parents must study the
Word中这样做家长必须研究
Word of God diligently for your counsel
上帝的话孜孜不倦地为你的忠告
ease who are parents to become good at
轻松谁是父母擅长
teaching God's Word they must be first
教导上帝的话语必须先行
good at studying it they must become
善于研究它们必须成为
Christians who live it in their own
基于自己的基督徒
lives who are making progress in regard
谁在 方面取得进展的生活
to sanctification and then they must
要成圣，然后他们必须
study more to understand how the nuances
学习更多，了解细微差别
of the word apply to each stage of life
这个词适用于生命的每个阶段
each particular situation in their
他们的每一个特殊情况
children's lives the result is worth the
孩子的生命结果是值得的
effort unequally yoked dad lead your
努力不平等地把爸爸带到你身边
home God's grace will be sufficient for
回家上帝的恩典就足够了
you know the word and teach wisdom to
你知道这个词并教导智慧
each of your children Christian couple
你的每个孩子基督徒夫妇
work together to create a home that is
共同创造一个家园
focused on the Word of God and is
专注于上帝的话语，是
permeated by living its truth single
由住它的道理单一渗透
mother you can do this believe that
妈妈，你能做到这一点相信
God's promises will be enough for you
上帝的承诺对你来说已经足够了
may God be glorified in your motives as
愿上帝在你的动机中得到荣耀
parents your effort in evangelism and
父母你的努力在传福音和
your effort in teaching and training now
你现在在教学和培训方面的努力
let's take a deeper look at the goal of
让我们深入了解一下目标
parenting as stated earlier the goal of
育儿为前面所述的目标
parenting is to honor God we're now on
养育是为了尊重我们现在所处的上帝
the at the middle of page 167 and so in
在第167页的中间等等
this section of our study we're going to
我们要研究的这一部分
consider some truths of the word to
考虑一下这个词的一些真理
further on
进一步
this goal of parenting honoring God
这个养育上帝的目标
above all else there are three primary
最重要的是有三个主要的
categories for this concept of honoring
这种荣誉概念的类别
God the first is the basic idea of
上帝首先是基本思想
itself honoring God God gives us a
本身尊重上帝给了我们一个
mission first Corinthians 10:31 whatever
任务首先是哥林多前书10:31无论如何
you do do all to the glory of God when
你做神时的荣耀
we measure each day of parenting by one
我们衡量每一天的育儿方式
thing above all others did I bring glory
最重要的是我带来了荣耀
to God then the other common questions
然后向上帝提出其他常见问题
diminish in importance is my kids
我孩子们的重要性降低了
smarter than most
比大多数人聪明
did she win her game is she attractive
她赢了她的比赛吗？
does my son love me you might think
我的儿子爱你，你可能会想
about these things but when the purpose
关于这些事情，但当目的
is honoring God they are not of primary
是尊重上帝， 他们不是主要的
importance instead every day is measured
重要的是每天都要衡量
by did I bring glory to God as a parent
作为父母，我是否将荣耀归于上帝
and you can't accomplish that every day
而你 每天 都无法做到这一点
no matter what happens no matter what
无论发生什么，无论发生什么
your kids do no matter how your spouse
无论你的配偶如何，你的孩子都会做
treats you point to in honoring God
对待你是为了纪念上帝
Ephesians 2:10 God is involved in every
以弗所书2:10上帝参与其中
moment of your life Ephesians 2:10 says
你生命的时刻以弗所书2:10说
we are his workmanship created in Christ
我们是他在基督里创造的工艺
Jesus for good works which God prepared
耶稣为上帝所预备的善行
beforehand that we should walk in them
事先我们应该走进去
God is intricately involved in your life
上帝错综复杂地参与了你的生活
in this way he takes each day and all
通过这种方式，他每天都需要
the dozens of things that might happen
可能发生的许多事情
and he arranges them to include specific
并且他安排他们包括具体的
things that parents can do to honor him
父母可以做的事情来纪念他
this gives great meaning to every hour
这给每个小时都有很大的意义
and every day we have the opportunity to
我们每天都有机会
bring glory to God
把荣耀带给上帝
so the mundane matters the monumental
所以世俗的重要里程碑
days matter
日子很重要
and God we makes each of those into the
而上帝让我们每个人都进入了
opportunity to do good for the sake of
机会， 为求做的好
honoring him if we can help parents view
如果我们可以帮助父母观看，就会尊重他
their ministry to their children in this
他们在这里为他们的孩子服务
way they'll be going a long way toward
他们将走很长的路
accomplishing the purpose of honoring
实现尊重的目的
God a second primary category in this
上帝是第二个主要类别
idea of honoring God is hope in Jesus
尊重上帝的想法是耶稣的希望
Christ Jesus Christ is our source of
基督耶稣基督是我们的源头
courage John 16:33 says this in the
勇气约翰福音16:33这样说
world you have tribulation but take
世界，你有苦难，但采取
courage I have overcome the world that
勇气我已经胜了世界上
was Jesus conclusion to the disciples
是耶稣对门徒的结论
the final thing he said to him take
他对他说的最后一件事拿
courage I have overcome the world many
勇气我已经战胜了许多世界
Christians today lack courage my friends
今天的基督徒缺乏我朋友的勇气
they are facing difficult problems that
他们所面对的困难问题，
appear to them to have no solution their
似乎他们有没有办法解决他们的
circumstances appear to be overwhelming
情况似乎是压倒性的
from their point of view hope is found
从他们的角度来看，希望是找到的
in John 16:33 Jesus declares that for
约翰福音16:33 耶稣宣布这是为了
the believer peace is found in him that
在他身上找到了信徒和平
peace comes when we take courage in
当我们鼓起勇气时，和平就来了
Jesus Christ because he overcame the
耶稣基督，因为他克服了
world because he resisted every
世界，因为他抵制每一个
temptation every day of his life here on
他生命中每一天的诱惑都在这里
earth and because he is in you and you
地球，因为他在你和你
are in him if you are a Christian you
如果你是基督徒，你 就在他里面
can take courage you can overcome the
可以采取勇气， 你可以克服
world also because Jesus Christ is your
世界也因为耶稣基督是你的
Lord that's why he says take courage I
主啊，这就是为什么他说勇气我
have overcome the world
战胜了这个世界
biblical counselor teach the parents who
圣经辅导员教导父母
come to you for counsel this truth this
来找你这个真相的忠告
this is vital for them in honoring God a
这对他们尊敬上帝至关重要
third factor necessary and honoring God
必要的第三个因素和尊重上帝
is the hope that there is in God's Word
希望在上帝的话语中存在
in the last hour Bob talked about hope
在最后一小时，鲍勃谈到了希望
from
从
the word in detail I just mentioned that
我刚才提到的那个细节
God gives us hope through the sufficient
上帝通过足够的东西给了我们希望
provision of his word 2nd Timothy 3:16
提到他的第二提摩太后书3:16
and 17 says that God can equip us for
17说上帝可以装备我们
every good work through his word and
通过他的话和每一件好事
that includes every situation the
包括每一种情况的
parents that come to you for help are
向你求助的父母是
going through also psalm 119 verse 11
经历了诗篇119节11节
the great enemy for every Christian
每个基督徒的大敌
parent is sin nothing destroys your
父母是罪，没有什么可以摧毁你的
ministry to your children like your own
对你的孩子的事工就像你自己一样
sin particularly if it's habitual or
特别是如果它是习惯性的或者是罪恶的
severe sin these types of sins confuse
严重的罪恶这些类型的罪恶混淆
kids in Christian homes they might think
他们可能会想到基督徒家中的孩子
if God is real why hasn't mommy ever
如果上帝是真实的，为什么还没有过妈咪
overcome her big sin apparent
克服她的大罪明显
selfishness might cause the Scriptures
自私可能导致圣经
to seem irrelevant to their kids
似乎与他们的孩子无关
obsession with work might convince them
对工作的痴迷可能会使他们信服
that God's love isn't real either
上帝的爱也不是真实的
because daddy believes in God and he
因为爸爸相信上帝和他
says he loves me but he's never here and
说他爱我， 但他永远不会在这里
he doesn't even know me
他甚至不认识我
so Psalm 19:1 19 verse 11 asks how can a
所以诗篇19：1个19 11节问怎么 能
young man keep his way pure and then it
年轻人保持他的方式纯净，然后它
answers by keeping it according to your
根据你的要求保留答案
word there is hope for every Christian
每个基督徒都有希望
parent that we can overcome all of the
父母，我们可以克服所有的
sins in our lives and as we
我们生活和我们一样的罪
systematically do so God will show our
系统地这样做，上帝会表明我们的
children that the word is true and that
孩子，这个词是真的那个
God's grace is real well we've defined
上帝的恩典是我们所定义的真实
the purpose of parenting which is to
育儿的目的是为了
honor God now let's consider what it
尊重上帝现在让我们考虑它是什么
looks like when that purpose is in
看起来像是在那个目的
practice
实践
in Philippians 1 Paul writes about his
在腓立比书1保罗写到他的
incarceration for at least two years
监禁至少两年
he's been chained to a different Roman
他被拴在一个不同的罗马人身上
guard every few hours those Roman guards
每隔几个小时守卫那些罗马卫兵
in all probability didn't think highly
很可能并没有高度重视
of Paul a Jewish man who now became a
保罗是一个犹太人，现在变成了一个
Christian there were strong warriors
克里斯蒂安有强大的战士
usually veterans of war there was
通常战争的退伍军人有
something about his appearance that was
一些关于他的外表，这是
not impressive maybe he was a small man
并不令人印象深刻，也许他是一个小男人
but he was different than them in many
但他在许多方面与他们不同
ways what purpose did Paul have during
保罗在这期间的目的是什么？
his time of incarceration he talks about
他的监禁时间，他谈到
it in Philippians 1 verses 20 and 21 he
它在腓立比书1节20和21节
says it is my eager expectation and hope
说这是我渴望的期望和希望
that I will not be at all ashamed but
我不会感到羞耻但是
that with full courage now as always
现在一如既往地充满勇气
Christ will be honored in my body
基督将在我的身体中获得荣耀
whether by life or by death for to me to
无论是生，是死的给我
live is Christ and to die is gain Paul
活就是基督，死就是保罗
could accomplish his purpose every
每个人都能实现他的目的
single day he could boldly exalt Christ
有一天，他可以大胆地高举基督
there were probably three choices for
可能有三种选择
him for at least a couple of years he's
他至少有几年了
had the the one option another day of
另一天有另一种选择
being chained and sitting with these
被束缚和坐在一起
guys but he's brought glory and honor to
球员，但他带来了荣耀和荣誉
God he's sharing the gospel with him and
上帝，他正在和他分享福音
many have come to Christ he talks about
很多人来到基督面前他说过
that earlier in Chapter 1 he could also
在第1章的早些时候， 他也可以
be set free at this imprisonment he
他被判入狱
eventually is set free and he returns to
最终被释放，他回归
his ministry to the churches and then
他对教会的事工然后
the other possibility was that one of
另一种可能性就是其中之一
these guys would be bringing a sword and
这些家伙会带来剑
this would be the last day of his life
这将是他生命中的最后一天
that didn't happen in this incarceration
在这次监禁中没有发生过这种情况
but in the next one and his purpose then
但在下一个和他的目的呢
would be to show every person in that
将向每个人展示
room what it looks like when a believer
房间看起来像是一个信徒
in Jesus Christ goes home forever
耶稣基督永远回家
but he had thought about this a lot and
但他已经考虑了很多这个问题
he had plenty of time to think and he
他有足够的时间去思考和他
had come to the conclusion that he was
已经得出结论，他是
going to boldly exalt Christ whichever
要大胆地高举基督为准
of these things happened in Philippians
这些事情发生在腓立比书中
4 verse 11 he says that he's learned to
4节11节他说他已经学会了
be content I believe that's a reflection
满足我相信这是一种反思
of the result of Philippians 1 20 and 21
腓立比书1 20和21的结果
he learned to be content because he had
他学会了满足，因为他有
the purpose of honoring God and he knew
尊重上帝的目的， 他知道
that he could accomplish that purpose
他可以完成这个目的
chained to the guard set free or
链接到卫兵或免费
executed nothing could stop him from
没有任何东西可以阻止他
honoring God whatever happened that day
无论那天发生什么，都要尊重上帝
so he was content because he
所以他很满意，因为他
accomplished the goal every day if we
如果我们每天都完成目标
can help Christian parents understand
可以帮助基督徒父母明白
that the goal isn't something to do with
我们的目标是没有事做
the behavior of their kids or if the
他们的孩子的行为或如果
kids appreciate them or all the other
孩子们欣赏他们或所有其他人
common things but rather to measure the
常见的事情，而不是衡量
day by the one thing did they bring
他们带来了一件事
glory and honor to God as a parent they
他们是父母的荣耀和荣耀
can be content every day because they
每天都可以满足，因为他们
can accomplish that goal every day no
每天都可以实现这个目标
matter what the circumstances are what
无论在什么情况下是什么
does this look like if the four-year-old
这看起来像是四岁的孩子
does well today I'll encourage him
今天做得好我会鼓励他
because he obeyed death and it'll be
因为他服从了死亡而且它会成功
easy to emulate Christ as we play
我们玩的时候很容易模仿基督
together if my four-year-old does not do
如果我四岁的孩子不这样做的话
well today if he hits his sister or lies
如果他打他的妹妹或谎言 今天好
to mommy I will calmly administer the
妈妈， 我会冷静地管理
consequences and teach him that sin is
后果并告诉他罪是
wrong and later I will be kind and play
错了，后来我会善良和发挥
with him in selfless love I will do each
与他无私的爱，我会做每一件事
of these things to boldly exalt Christ
这些事要大胆地高举基督
to honor God and my family in both cases
在这两种情况下 都要尊重上帝和我的家人
I will be content because I accomplished
我会满足，因为我完成了
the purpose I honored God in that
我在这方面尊敬上帝的目的
setting
设置
do you see that if Paul's purpose in
如果保罗的目的在于，你看到了吗？
Philippians 1 was freedom or a
腓立比书1是自由或自由
particular type of ministry or seeing
特殊类型的事工或看见
friends again that his life would have
朋友们再一次认为他的生活会有
been miserable it's a fact in the same
被很惨它在同一个事实
way parents who seek easy days or report
寻求轻松日子或报告的父母
cards with straight A's or being
直接A 或正在使用的卡片
respected as parents or perfect kids
被视为父母或完美的孩子
will not be content either but Paul did
保罗也不会满足
achieve his goal every day he honored
每天他都很 荣幸地实现自己的目标
Jesus Christ and so the parent who
耶稣基督等父母是谁
accomplishes the goal of honoring Jesus
实现了尊重耶稣的目标
Christ will be content regardless of the
无论如何，基督都会满足
consequences
后果
I should say regardless of the
无论如何，我应该说
circumstances let's consider a couple of
情况让我们考虑几个
more examples what does this look like
更多示例这是什么样的
in the life of a Christian parent the
在基督徒父母的生活中
unequally yoked parent can regard each
不平等的父母可以考虑每一个
day alike whether there was conflict
一天是否有冲突
with their mate over parenting or
与他们的伴侣而不是养育子女
whether it was a peaceful day with your
是不是和你平静的一天
spouse and a great day with the kids
配偶和孩子们度过了愉快的一天
either way the Christian can boldly
无论哪种方式，基督徒都可以大胆
exalt Christ by doing right when your
在你的时候做正确的事，来高举基督
teen lies you can honor God when your
青少年的谎言，你可以尊重上帝
teen bears fruit by bringing someone to
青少年通过带人来结果
Christ you can honor God when your 12
基督你可以在12岁时荣耀上帝
year old was respectful for the 39th day
一岁是尊重第39天
in a row you can exalt Christ for sure
你可以连续高举基督
but on the the day when your 12 year old
但在你12岁的那一天
has broken the house rule about the
已经破坏了有关的房子规则
internet you can exalt Christ on those
互联网你可以高举基督
days as well if your purpose is to
如果您的目的是为了
boldly exalt Christ nothing can stop you
大胆高举基督没有什么可以阻止你
well we've considered the purpose of
我们考虑过的目的
parenting to honor God and we've just
为了荣耀上帝而养育我们，我们就是这样
discussed the practice of honoring God
讨论尊重上帝的做法
now we're at the bottom of page 168 and
现在我们处于第168页的底部
our next section is the perspective of a
我们的下一部分是一个视角
gerrant with this purpose if we live to
如果我们活着就有这个目的的gerrant
honor God what do we think well there
尊重上帝我们在那里有什么好的想法
are many things but I want us to
有很多事情，但我希望我们能
consider three tonight first God is here
今晚考虑三个第一个上帝在这里
with me second the Scriptures address
在我的第二个经文地址
this situation and third I can obey God
这种情况和第三种我可以服从上帝
the Bible teaches that that God is here
圣经教导说上帝在这里
with me he's here with you too but you
和我在一起他也和你在一起
can't see him but he is he's here with
看不到他，但他和他在一起
me how do I know that the Bible says it
我怎么知道圣经说的呢
in acts 17 25 and 28 it says that he
在行为17 25和28中， 它说他
gives me life and breath and I'm alive
给了我生命和呼吸，我还活着
and I'm breathing so so God is here with
我呼吸，所以上帝在这里
me it also says that in him I live and
我也说，在我身边，我活着
move and exist and those things are
移动和存在，这些都是
happening too so God is here with me the
发生的事也是如此，上帝和我在一起了
Bible teaches that not only is God here
圣经教导说，不仅是上帝在这里
with me and you but he's also doing
跟我和你，但他也在做
things with us one is Romans 8:38 and 39
与我们同在的东西是罗马书8:38和39
he loves me and nothing can possibly
他爱我，没有什么可能
separate me from his love he's guarding
将我从他的爱中分开，他正在守护着
me he's protecting me what else is God
我，他在保护我，还有什么是上帝
doing well Romans 8:28 and 29 God is
做得好罗马书8:28和29神是
causing all things to work for my
导致所有的事情为我的工作
benefit he is causing each thing that
好处他使每个件事
happens to conform me more to the image
恰巧使我更符合图像
of Jesus Christ this is great news
耶稣基督这是个好消息
because my purpose is to boldly exalt
因为我的目的是大胆地提升
Christ my purpose is to honor God so God
基督我的目的是要尊敬上帝，所以上帝
is at work for this same goal
正在为这个目标而努力
so God is here with each of us and and
所以上帝和我们每个人在一起
he's doing a lot every minute also he
他每分钟都在做很多事情
may test my faith James 1 2 through 4 he
可以考验我的信仰詹姆斯12到4他
tests my faith so he can strengthen me
测试我的信仰， 这样他就能加强我
to overcome sin
克服罪恶
and then give me the opportunity to
然后给我机会
glorify him by enduring the difficult
通过忍受困难来荣耀他
times so God is here he's here with me
所以上帝在这里他和我在一起
and he's here with you and he's also
他和你在一起，他也是
there with each Christian parent who is
有每个基督徒父母是谁
struggling his immense love causes him
挣扎着他巨大的爱情导致了他
to do these things just mentioned in my
做我刚刚提到的这些事情
life today in your life today and in
在今天和今天的生活中
that Christian parents life God is here
基督徒父母的生活上帝在这里
with me
跟我
God is here with me
上帝与我同在
this is an important truth in the in the
这是在在一个重要的真理
word this is an important truth for
这是一个重要的事实
parents to understand we say with me one
父母了解我们跟我说的一个
time God is here with me
上帝与我同在
God is here with me let's transition to
上帝和我在一起让我们过渡到
the next thing
接下来的事
a parent with hope knows that God is
有希望的父母知道上帝是
here with me he or she also knows that
在这里，他或她也知道这一点
the Scriptures address every situation
圣经解决了所有情况
God's Word is so comprehensive that God
上帝的话是如此全面，以至于上帝
causes it to be living and active and he
导致它被活泼的他
exposes the thoughts and intentions of
暴露了思想和意图
our hearts which he knows so the
我知道他们的心
scriptures address every situation
经文解决每一种情况
including the thoughts and intentions of
包括的想法和意图
my heart as I'm going through these
我的心脏，因为我经历这些
situations and God has told us here in
情况和上帝告诉我们在这里
Hebrews 4 12 and 13 that he will cause
他将引起 希伯来书4章12和13章
the word to be living and active and
这个词是生活和活跃的
exposed some of that perhaps for the
暴露出一些的，也许 对于
benefit of us being conformed to the
我们受益于我们的利益
image of Christ like it says in Romans
像罗马人所说的基督形象
8:28 and 29 so the scriptures address
8:28 和29所以经文说明
each situation and God causes the word
每种情况和上帝都会导致这个词
to be living and active what's the
生活和活跃是什么
result of the scriptures in the life of
经文中的经文结果
a believer God's Word will make you
一个信徒， 上帝的话会使你成为
wiser than your enemies your teachers or
比你的敌人更聪明你的老师或
people who have lived longer
生活得更久的人
so the Scriptures address every
所以圣经解决了每一个问题
situation and they enable me to do right
情况，他们让我做对了
in every situation this includes the
在任何情况下，这包括
hard questions in life how do I parent
生活中的难题我如何做父母
my child in these circumstances at this
我的孩子在这种情况下
time does the word address that it does
时间这个词是否解决了它的问题
and what we teach our counsel leads to
以及我们教导我们的建议的方法
do and what we strive to do in our own
做我们自己努力做的事情
lives as moms and dads we search the
生活在我们寻找的妈妈和爸爸
specific scriptures on parenting we
关于养育我们的具体经文
examine our own hearts we respond to God
检查我们自己的心，我们回应上帝
as he judges our goals and desires we
因为他判断我们的目标，并渴望我们
choose to obey Him and to replace any
选择服从他，并更换任何
sin that he's exposed with righteousness
他以公义暴露他的罪
and then we also evaluate what our
然后我们也评估我们的
children want and think and do in light
孩子们想要，思考和做事
of the scriptures and then we discuss
经文然后我们讨论
these things for their spouse the
这些东西对于他们的配偶来说
scriptures address every situation and
经文解决每一个情况，
God will also use his word to equip the
上帝也会用他的话来装备
Christian parent for every good work so
基督徒的父母为每一项好工作所以
how can I become a father who can
我怎么能成为一个可以的父亲
accurately teach God's Word sometimes
有时准确地教导上帝的话语
people say you don't know my kids and I
人们说你不认识我的孩子和我
say but I do know your God it is
说，但我确实知道你的上帝
possible for you to be able to teach the
可以让你能够教导
scriptures to your children you're not
给你孩子的经文你不是
being tempted beyond what you're able so
被诱惑超出你的能力
we help the Christian parent to study
我们帮助基督徒的父母学习
the word and to implement the word in
这个词并用来实现这个词
their own lives so a Christian parent
他们自己的生活如此基督徒的父母
who hears the truth of the word views
谁听到了意见一词的真相
their setting as a parent as this God is
他们像上帝一样是父母
here with me the Scriptures address
这里有我的经文地址
every situation in life and
生活中的每一种情况
I can obey God I can obey God because
我可以顺从上帝，我可以顺服上帝，因为
the Scriptures will help me to change
圣经将帮助我改变
first Peter 2 1 through 3 compares the
第一个彼得2 1到3比较了
Ministry of the word by God in the
教育部上帝的字
Christians life to the baby who's
基督徒的生活对宝宝来说是谁的
getting mom's milk that's all the baby
得到妈妈的奶，这都是宝宝
needs it's all the baby wants it's the
需要它是所有宝宝想要它的
food and nourishment that he needs and
他需要的食物和营养
he grows in the same way the Scriptures
他以与圣经相同的方式成长
are God's tool to enable that Christian
是上帝启用基督徒的工具
parent no matter how difficult the
父母无论多么艰难
situation to grow in respect to
关于增长的情况
salvation this is good news so the
救恩这是好消息所以
Christian parent has this perspective in
基督徒父母在这个角度
each scene of life God is here with me
每一个生命场景上帝都在我身边
the Scriptures address this situation I
圣经解决了这种情况我
can obey God my spouse hates me today
可以服从上帝，我的配偶今天恨我
well God is here with me the Scriptures
上帝在这里与我同在圣经
do address this situation so I I will
不解决这一情况，以便II将
forgive her and love her and I can obey
原谅她，爱她，我可以服从
God new problems with the kids
上帝与孩子们的新问题
God is here with me the Scriptures
上帝与我同在圣经
address this situation so I'm going to
解决这种情况所以我要去
be able to figure out how the scriptures
能够弄清楚经文如何
address this matter with the kids it
与孩子们解决这个问题 它
will be possible to figure it out and
将有可能搞清楚
once I do I can obey God God's grace
一旦我这样做，我就可以服从上帝的恩典
will be sufficient and I want to obey
就足够了，我想服从
God great days with the family
上帝与家人共度美好时光
God is here with me and how kind he is
上帝与我同在，他是多么善良
the Scriptures address every situation
圣经解决每一个情况
and on those days it's James 1:17 every
在那些日子里，每个人都是雅各书1:17
good thing bestowed every gift is from
赠送的每件礼物都是好东西
above and we can obey God and so can our
在上面，我们可以服从上帝，我们也可以
families so God is here with me the
家人所以上帝和我在一起
Scriptures addressed this situation I
圣经解决了这种情况我
can obey God
可以顺从上帝
we say this with me a couple of times
我们这几次和我说这个
God is here with me the Scriptures
上帝与我同在圣经
address this situation I can obey God
解决这种情况我可以顺从上帝
God is here with me the Scriptures
上帝与我同在圣经
address this situation I can obey God if
解决这种情况我可以顺从上帝
I can convince struggling parents that
我可以说服挣扎的父母
these things are true and if they will
这些都是真的，如果他们愿意的话
believe the Scriptures and live
相信圣经并活着
accordingly many of the problems and
因此很多问题和
their families will be solved this is
他们的家人将会解决这个问题
our environment this is our world these
我们的环境这是我们的世界
things are what's true about the
事情是真实的
difficult ministry that a parent has
父母有困难的事工
well we've seen all this hope we've seen
好吧，我们已经看到了我们所见过的所有希望
how the purpose for parents is to honor
父母的目的是如何兑现
God we've seen how the purpose looks in
上帝， 我们已经看到了目的的样子
practice by Paul's example and we've
保罗的榜样和我们的实践
considered the perspective of a parent
考虑了父母的观点
who has the proper purpose let's think
谁有正确的目的让我们思考
about the practices of a parent with
关于父母的做法
purpose these are the practices of the
目的这些都是 的 做法
parent who has that purpose of honoring
有尊重目的的父母
and glorifying God and who is trusting
并且荣耀上帝和信靠谁
in God's promises who believes that God
在上帝的应许中，他相信上帝
is here with them who believes that the
与他们在一起谁相信
Scriptures address every situation and
圣经解决了所有情况
believes that they can obey God they
相信他们可以服从上帝
love their children as they're loved by
爱他们的孩子， 因为他们被他们所爱
Christ they do teach and train and lead
基督， 他们教导，训练和领导
and they are fearless in honoring God in
他们在敬畏上帝时无所畏惧
these things I'd like to tell you a
这些东西我想告诉你一个
brief story a little bit of my own
简短的故事我自己的一点点
testimony I am a man like you a sinner
见证我是一个像你一个罪人的男人
saved by grace
被恩典救了
I'm very thankful for the blood of
我非常感谢血液
Christ I'm a person who's described in
基督我是一个被描述的人
1st Corinthians 1:26 to 31 as a typical
哥林多前书1:26至31为典型的
Christian
基督教
I'm one of those people who doesn't come
我是那些不来的人之一
from a noble or mighty family neither
从贵族或强大的家族也不
does my wife
我的妻子
neither of us came from Christian homes
我们都不是来自基督徒家园
but according to 1st Corinthians 1:26
但根据哥林多前书1:26
231 sometimes God is pleased to use
231有时上帝很乐意使用
people like us to say to the world hey
像我们这样的人对世界说嘿
look what I can do with a guy like that
看看我能用这样的人做些什么
and so I'm thankful for his grace I'd
所以我很感激他的恩典，我想
like to tell you just a little bit about
想告诉你只是一点点
something that happened a few summers
发生在几个夏天的事情
ago Julie and I were having lunch with
前朱莉和我有午餐
our two kids who at that time were adult
我们这两个孩子当时都是成年人
Christians walking with God praise God
与上帝同行的基督徒赞美上帝
were so thankful for his work in them
是他在他们的工作 ，以便感谢
and they were at the time 22 and 23
他们在22和23时
we were we were sitting at an outdoor
我们是坐在户外的
restaurant in Marina del Rey having
Marina del Rey的餐厅
lunch and somehow there was we started
午餐，不知怎的，我们开始了
talking about some of the things that
谈论一些事情
happened in the past and it was things
发生在过去，这是事情
like hey Dad remember when I was 14 and
就像嘿爸爸记得我14岁的时候
and you said that and you did that what
而你说那就是那样做的
were you thinking why did you do that
你在想为什么这么做
and so the answer would be something
所以答案应该是什么
like wow you know as the years have gone
哇，你知道多年过去了
by and through the word I've realized
通过我已经意识到的这个词
you know that was wrong you know and
你知道错了，你知道和
here's how the scriptures addressed that
这是经文如何解决这个问题
I don't think I ever came back to you
我不认为我曾经回复过你
and ask for your forgiveness but I did
并请求你的原谅，但我做到了
repent of sinning in ways like that
以这样的方式忏悔犯罪
against you will you forgive me and then
反对你，你会原谅我吗？
there were other questions like hey
还有其他问题， 比如嘿
remember when you were 10 and you were
记得你10岁的时候 和你在一起
going through this particular set of
经历这组特定 的
circumstances for a few months and you
几个月，你的情况
know our kids were became Christians at
知道我们的孩子们成了基督徒
a pretty young age so yeah you were a
一个相当年轻的年龄，所以是的，你是一个
believer them but what was it like what
相信他们，但它是什么样的
was going on between you and the Lord
在你和主之间发生着
during those times and we all felt the
在那些时候，我们都感受到了
comfort and freedom in Christ to talk
谈话中的安慰和自由
openly and honestly about these things
公开诚实地谈论这些事情
what I realized that day was that first
我第一次意识到那一天
Corinthians 15:10
哥林多前书15:10
is true Paul said I am what I am by
是真的保罗说我就是我的样子
God's grace we were a group of four
上帝的恩典我们是四人一组
christians who for many years sought to
多年来一直寻求的 基督徒
bring glory and honor to God and Julie
为上帝和朱莉带来荣耀和荣耀
and I his parents Julie and I as a
我和他的父母朱莉和我一样
married couple Skye and ELISA as
已婚夫妇斯凯和ELISA为
Christians and as children but like
基督徒和孩子，但喜欢
everyone we each had sin to overcome we
我们每个人都有罪来克服我们
each had weaknesses to overcome through
每个人都有可以克服的弱点
the scriptures but on that day it was
经文，但那天是
such a wonderful time with the Lord to
与主如此美好的时光
consider together all these things that
综合考虑所有这些事情
God had done in so many different
上帝已经做了很多不同的事情
circumstances sometimes in spite of some
有时甚至有些情况
of the other members of the family
该家庭的其他成员
sometimes with a with the beneficial
有时与一个有益的
help of other members of the family but
帮助其他家庭成员但是
the bottom line of it all really was
这一切的底线 确实是
that praise and glory to God anything
是赞美和荣耀归给神什么
that we are we are because of His grace
因为他的恩典 ，我们就是这样
he worked he worked through the word he
他曾通过他的话，他的工作
worked through His grace even in the
甚至在他的工作中也通过他的恩典
efforts of us in ministering to each
我们为每个人服务的努力
other in the incomplete way that we
其他我们不完整的方式
could he worked and that's the cause of
他能工作吗？这是他的原因
what was going on there
发生了什么事情有
that day for people who are still
对那些静止的人来说那一天
seeking to bring glory and honor to
寻求带来荣耀和荣誉
Jesus Christ and have sought to help
耶稣基督和寻求帮助
each other go that direction I tell you
彼此走向我告诉你的那个方向
the story just to encourage you if if
这个故事只是为了鼓励你
you're the parents of young kids if it's
如果是的话，你就是小孩的父母
the early time in this whole process
整个过程的早期时间
if you counsel people at different
如果你为不同的人提供咨询
stages the purpose in parenting is to
阶段在养育子女的目的是
honor God and for the parent the goal is
尊重上帝，为父母的目标是
to do everything you possibly can to
尽你所能去做
honor God and we and we've looked at a
尊重上帝和我们，我们看了一眼
few different specific characteristics
几个不同的具体特征
of that do everything you can to honor
那尽你所能 兑现
God and then if by God's grace someday
上帝，然后如果有一天上帝的恩典
there
那里
our children who are Christians if by
我们的孩子， 如果是基督徒
God's grace someday there are children
有一天上帝的恩典有孩子
who are Christians who are walking with
谁是与之同行的基督徒
God you can all sit together and say
上帝，你都可以 坐在一起说
praise You Lord we are what we are by
赞美你主我们就是我们所拥有的
God's grace
上帝的恩典
you
您